本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
我们是宝石战士
We are the crystal gems
终日拯救世界
We'll always save the day
■
时间轴： Enpistu  shortcut
如果你感到怀疑
And if you think we can't
我们总能找到出路
We'll always find a way
■
翻译： FL1.2  Peace.
所以全世界人们
That's why the people of this world
■
校订： violin1443  Enpistu
都信任
believe in
石榴
Garnet
紫晶
Amethyst
和珍珠
And Pearl
宇宙小子  第一季第十七  十八集
Steven Universe  S01E17E18  Lion2 the Movie/Beach Party
还有史蒂文
And Steven!
狮子2  电影
■
后期： FL1.2  Enpistu  liloelva
有人说
你教不会
一只老狗
新把戏
除非你是
直升飞狗
这个二月
毛绒绒遇上旋翼
我明白你为什么最爱这套电影了
I can see why this is your favorite film franchise!
没错
That's right.
在一个人性已被推到悬崖边的世界
In a world where humanity is pushed to the brink,
结果最有人情味的却是一只狗  直升机
it turns out that the one who is most human is a dog...copter.
还有你看到导弹是从哪里飞出来的了么
And did you see where that missile came out of?!
看到了
Yeah.
我只是希望电影能忠于原著
I just hope it stays faithful to the book.
宝石战士回来了
The gems are back.
你好
Greetings.
哇  你好啊  康妮
W-well, hello, Connie!
见到你真是惊喜呀
What a surprise to see you!
我们要去看一场关于能飞的古怪狗狗的电影
We're gonna watch a movie about a wacky flying dog!
给她们看  康妮
Show them, Connie!
我想说的是  这电影可不止这些哦
I mean, it's about much more than that.
即将              上映
简单得很
That's easy.
啥
Wha?
既然有了魔法  谁还需要去看什么电影呢
Who needs to go see movies when you've got ♪ magic?! ♪
别显摆了  紫晶
Stop showing off, Amethyst.
康妮保证说这部电影比任何魔法都要好
Connie promises this movie's even better than any magic!
我可没说过
I did not say that.
你们再瞧这儿
And check this out!
我们准备了好多零食
We got our own snacks!
我父母叫我不要在电影院里买零食
My parents say I'm not allowed to buy snacks at the theater.
所以  我们就不在电影院里买东西了
So we're not buying anything at the theater.
嗷呜嗷呜
Nom noms!
给我吃
Feed me!
想都别想  紫晶  这些都是我和康妮要看电影的时候吃的
Hands off, Amethyst! these are for Connie and me to share at the movie.
说到这里
Speaking of which,
我们要怎么到电影院呢  还真有点远
how are we getting to the theater? It's kind of far.
别担心  我早就想好啦
Don't worry. I've got it covered.
今天我们要出去得很有型
Today we're gonna travel in style.
隆重介绍  最上档次的豪华交通工具
Introducing the finest in luxury transportation...
狮子
Lion!
你个小懒球
You little goofball.
你有只宠物狮子
You have a pet Lion?!
狮子就算是宠物吧
Lion is sort of like a pet.
虽然他大多数时候都是自己忙自己的
He does his own thing most of the time, though.
瞧  谁知道他哪里弄来的这个
See? Who knows where he got that.
史蒂文  你生活中到处充满了魔法和神奇的事物
Wow, Steven. Everything in your life is so awesome and magical.
而我生活中最令人激动的事就是网球练习了
The most exciting thing in my life is tennis practice.
正手拉球
Forehand!
反手击球
Backhand!
扣球绝地杀
Overhead death strike!
网球超酷的
Tennis is rad!
最后那个是我编的啦
Well, I made up that last one.
我觉得狮子在催我们快点出发了
I think Lion says we should hurry up and go.
要不就是他只是打了个哈欠
Or maybe he was just yawning.
总之  我们去看电影吧
Anyway, let's go to the movie!
出发喽
And we're off!
狮子  我想让你带我们去看电影
Lion, I want you to take us to the movie.
好吧  你根本没在听我说
Okay, you're not listening to me.
狮子没怎么经过训练
Lion isn't trained very well.
但我也没怎么经过训练  所以我们是
But I'm not trained very well either, so we're a --
等等狮子  不要跑到海里去
Wait, Lion! Don't go in the ocean!
你能水上漂
You can walk on water?
你会做这么多事  为什么都不告诉我
Why don't you tell me you can do these things you do?!
嘿哟
Heyo!
你确定他知道要往哪里去吗
Are you sure he knows where he's going?
可能这是条近路
Maybe it's a short cut?
他以前也这样吗
Has he ever done this?
不  这是第一次
No, this is new!
你还好吗
Are you okay?
刚那真是太酷了
That was really cool.
狮子
Lion!
等等  你要去哪里呀
Wait! Where are you going?!
这是不是就是
Is this one of those...
你之前跟我说的魔法宝石的地方
magic gem places that you've told me about?
对  魔法宝石的地方
Yep. magic gem place.
狮子  通常我是老在捣腾这些  但这里不是电影院啊
Lion, normally I'm all about this stuff, but this is not the movies.
你这是什么意思  狮子
What does that mean, Lion?
你到底是什么意思啊
What does that even mean?
也许他把你带到这儿  有什么原因呢
What if he brought you here for a reason?
可能吧  但如果我们再不快点  我们就要错过片头广告
Well, maybe, but if we don't hurry, we're gonna miss the commercials,
还要错过预告片了
and then we might miss the previews,
而且我们还得有时间找到靠近屏幕又不要太近的绝佳座位
and we still have to find the perfect seats near the front but not too close.
嘿  我觉得它喜欢你
Hey. I think it likes you!
我的手被卡住了
My hand's stuck!
怎么都
It won't...
拿不下来
come off!
坚持住
Hang on!
天呐  这卡得也太紧了
Man, that's really stuck on good.
我猜我们得把它砍下来了
I guess we'll have to chop it off.
什么
What?!
嘿  是剑诶
Hey, swords!
不
No!
你怎么做到的
How'd you do that?
我不知道
I don't know.
再来一遍  再来一遍
Do it again! do it again!
好吧
Okay.
怎么样
Anything?
没怎样  来
No. Here.
你这是要干什
What are you --
你这是在干什么呀
Hey! What are you doing?
说不定我
Maybe if I do...
这样的话
this!
别这样  我怕痒
Wait, I'm ticklish.
快停下  快停下  我要尿出来啦
Wait. Stop. Stop. I'm gonna pee!
瞧瞧这些装甲们
Look at all this armor!
按我的鼻子  按我的鼻子
Press my nose. press my nose!
那些是光能大炮么
Are those light cannons?
下一个
Next!
斧子
Axes!
荆棘链球
Spiky chain balls!
美利坚合众国
合众为一
1 美分
一块大
A giant...
硬币
penny?
是不是说它比普通大小的硬币更值钱呢
Does that mean its worth more than a regular penny?
哇  好像有几"分"道理
Well, that would make "cents."
这真的很棒  只是
This is so great, but...
我有一种感觉  觉得自己是不应该呆在这里的
I get the feeling, though, I'm not really supposed to be here.
我想要你在这
I want you here!
我是说  我不想你在这里  我猜是狮子想我们在这
I mean, I don't want you here. I guess Lion wants us here.
但是我想我们一起去看电影
But I want us to be at the movies!
我还想看很多的爆炸场面
And I want to see lots of explosions.
我们应该担心一下这个吗
Should we be worried about this?
狮子看上去不怎么担心
Lion doesn't seem to be worried.
快跑
Run!
康妮
Connie!
史蒂文  小心
Steven! Look out!
史蒂文
Steven!
我们怎么办
What do we do?!
康妮
Connie!
我的泡泡
My bubble.
狮子
Lion!
带我们离开这里  求你了狮子
Get us out of here! Lion, please!
搞啥
What?
现在你倒带我们来电影院了
Now you take us to the movies?
康妮  等下  我这里有能用的东西
Connie, here. I have something for that.
抱歉  已经不太冰了
Sorry. They're not that cold.
谢了
Thanks.
好吧  来都来了  要进去吗
Well, we're here. Shall we go in?
没关系的  这  这事就这么算了吧
That's okay. L-let's just forget about it.
我  我很抱歉
I-I'm sorry!
我总是搞砸一切  不是吗
I ruined everything, didn't I?
我都搞不懂你为什么会跟我玩
I don't know why you hang out with me.
每次我都弄得一团糟
I mess stuff up all the time.
我才搞不懂你为什么会跟我玩呢
I don't know why you hang out with me!
跟你比起来  我可要没意思多了
I'm so much more... less interesting than you!
而且很明显你还有着什么魔法使命要完成
And obviously you have some sort of magical destiny.
为什么你还会去关心直升飞狗之类的东西呢
Why would you even care about something like Dogcopter?
为什么  因为那是直升飞狗诶
Why?! Because it's Dogcopter!
他是只狗  又是架直升机  还是警察
He's a dog and a helicopter and a cop!
他从屁股里射出导弹  而且他要去拯救世界
He shoots missiles out his butt, and he's gonna save the world!
直升飞狗可是非常炫酷又重要  对我来说
Dogcopter is very cool and important... to me.
可我不是直升飞狗
Well, I'm no Dogcopter.
怎么了
What the --
哦不
Oh, no!
是那个到处开火的机器
It's the robot shooty thing!
我们要怎么才能打败它
How are we supposed to beat it?
狮子  我们该怎么做
Lion, what do we do?
这可真奇怪  是吧
This is weird, right?
你脑袋里有一把剑
You have a sword in your head?!
你会做这么多事  为什么都不告诉我
Why don't you tell me you can do these things you do?!
要过来了
It came through!
我要怎么用这东西呀
What do I do with this?!
当心
Watch out!
正手拉球
Forehand!
反手击球
Backhand!
扣球  绝地杀
Overhead... death strike!
就像网球练习一样
Just like tennis practice.
魔法使命练习
Magical destiny practice.
嗨
Hi!
你好
Hello.
两张儿童票  和一张狮子票  看《直升飞狗》
Two kids and one Lion to see "Dogcopter".
你们有会员卡吗
Do you have a rewards card?
书里是这样的吗
Was that in the book?
他们自由发挥了一些
They're taking some liberties.
沙滩派对
你还好吗  史蒂文
You okay, Steven?
还好啦
I've seen better days.
珍珠  我受伤了嘛
Pearl, I got a boo-boo.
噢  你省省吧
Oh, walk it off.
它来了
Here it comes.
你们来分散它的注意
You all distract it!
给这玩意儿看看我们的实力  各位
Let's show this thing what we're made of, guys!
我们之前一个小时都在干这个啊
What do you think we've been doing for the past hour?
（注：Duck也有"鸭子"的意思）
快蹲下
Duck!
伙计  我可没看到鸭  嘎
Man, I don't see any d... Quack!
轮到史蒂文了
Steven's turn!
哎哟  它还带刺呢
Yup! It's got spikes!
没关系
It's okay!
还有石榴呢
Here comes Garnet!
砸碎那胖河豚
Smash that puff!
啊  天哪  我们搞砸了
Aw, man! We blew it!
呃  豁出去了
Ugh, whatever!
紫晶
Amethyst!
光是把它打飞到很远的地方
Smacking it really far away
根本不解决问题
doesn't solve anything!
我们应该把它毁掉
We needed to destroy it.
这下它就要回头再来了
Now it's just gonna come back later.
对啊  那我们就回头再对付它咯
Yeah, so we'll deal with it later.
我们去找石榴吧
Let's get Garnet.
她掉到木板路那边了
She landed by the boardwalk.
你能不能吱一声啊
Would you answer me?!
你不仅砸了我的招牌
You've wrecked my sign
还傻坐着不说话
and now you're just sitting up there!
我们难道是在开瞪眼大赛吗
Are we engaged in a secret staring contest?!
石榴  你还好吗
Garnet! Are you okay?
我没事儿
I'm fine.
嗨  史蒂文
Hi, Steven.
瞧这地儿被砸的哟
This place is wrecked!
来击个掌
Give me one down low.
你没什么值得表扬的  紫晶
No accolades for you, Amethyst.
她把那胖河豚打回了海里
She knocked the puffer fish back out into the ocean!
怪我咯
Narc!
我们回神庙重新集结吧
Let's regroup back at the temple.
你们往哪儿跑
Where are you going?
我的招牌可怎么办啊  史蒂文
What about my sign? Steven!
你朋友都在胡闹些什么
What is wrong with your friends?
其中一个砸了我的招牌
One of them busts up my sign,
然后她们就全都像耍杂技似的飞走了
then they all just jump into the sky like some circus act
根本不知道要帮忙
without even offering to help!
但是  披萨先生
But, Mr. Pizza!
老爸  安静些吧
Dad, pipe down!
噢  我是不是打扰了您老的美容觉啊
Oh! Did I interrupt your beauty sleep?
我这么美才不缺美容觉呢
I don't need sleep to look pretty.
你给我听好了  小姑娘
Now you listen here, young woman!
科菲  你发出的噪音
Kofi, you are going to wake this fish
都快要让这鱼起死回生了
from the dead with all the noise you're keeping.
噢  太迟了
Oh! Too late.
"科菲  你太吵了  啊"  呜呼
"Kofi, you so loud! Aaaaah!" Bleh.
耿佳  你真逗
Gunga, you're so funny.
妈  别再开玩笑了
Mom, quit joking around!
你看看她们对我的招牌做了些什么
Look what they did to my sign!
我的天呀
Cheese on bread!
你敢相信吗
Can you believe it?
你明明是个好孩子  史蒂文
You're such a nice boy, Steven.
你为什么要和那些禽兽鬼混
Why do you hang out with those animals?
她们才不是禽兽
They're not animals!
她们是宝石战士 她们是保护人类的
They're the Crystal Gems and they protect humanit...
我听够了
I've heard enough!
嘿  姑娘们
Hey, girls,
咱们的手机似乎都响了呢
I think I hear all of our cellphones ringing.
耿佳  你的听力真是好
Gunga, your hearing is so good.
史蒂文  告诉你的朋友们
Steven, you can tell your friends
她们正式被禁止进入炖鱼披萨
that they are officially banned from Fish Stew Pizza!
等等  什么  科菲  这不公平
Wait! What?! Kofi, that's not fair!
这只是一次意外
This was just an accident!
我们能不能就 那个
What if we just, like,
让胖河豚恣意遨游啊
let it roam free?
没戏
That's not an option.
-嘿  史蒂文  -我有个坏消息  各位
-  Hey, Steven. - I've got bad news, everyone.
你们被禁止进入炖鱼披萨了
You've all been banned from Fish Stew Pizza.
噢  呃  没关系
Oh! Uh, that's okay.
反正那里的披萨也不好吃
That pizza wasn't even good.
你们对此不感到难过吗
Aren't you guys upset about this?
一点也不啊
Not at all.
但他们是我们的邻居
But these are our neighbors.
现在我们对此也无能为力
There's nothing we can do about that now.
现在我们必须找到
Right now we have to figure out a way
解决胖河豚的办法
to take care of that puffer fish.
可你们为什么拯救人类呢
What's the point of saving people
人类甚至不让你进入他们的披萨店
if they're just gonna ban you from their pizza shops?
我们救人不图感恩
We don't do it for thanks.
对啊  看到没  你人多好啊
Yeah, see? That is so nice of you!
披萨一家都不知道
The Pizzas don't even know!
他们如果肯花些时间与你们相处
If they got to spend some time with you,
就能知道你们是多么幽默机智又神秘的人了
they'd see how fun and smart and mysterious you are.
呵  神秘
Heh. Mysterious.
我有主意了  我会在神庙前的沙滩上
I know! I'll throw a little party on the beach
办一个小派对
in front of the temple!
只有我们和披萨一家
Just us and the Pizzas!
不知道  史蒂文  我是说
I don't know, Steven. I mean ...
别担心  我会安排好一切的
Don't worry! I'll take care of everything!
这派对一定超棒
Man, this is gonna be so good!
-嘿  史蒂文  -嘿
- Hey, Steven. - Hey!
你的小派对准备好了吗
Got everything ready for your little party?
差不多  就剩一样了
Yeah. There's one more thing.
这是要干嘛
What's this for?
我想让你们换身衣服
I was thinking you guys could change your outfits.
我们现在穿的衣服有问题吗
What's wrong with what we have on now?
没什么
Nothing!
我只是觉得穿得休闲一些
I just thought it would be nice
会更好
to go kind of casual.
这地址没有错吧
Is this the right address?
我还没来过沙滩的这一侧呢
I've never seen this side of the beach before.
天哪  他们来了
Oh, man, they're here.
快去换衣服
Hurry up and change.
各位  到这里来  大家好啊
Over here, everyone! Hi!
-嘿  史蒂文  -你好
- Hey, Steven. - Hello.
你们今天怎么样呀
How're you all doing today?
小店被砸坏就只能关门了
The shop is closed today because it's broken.
呃  噢  那可真是呃
Uh... uh, oh! That sounds, uh...
嘿  我是闻到热狗的香味了吗
Hey, do I smell hot dogs?
快告诉我热狗在哪里
Show me where the hot dogs are.
这边请  各位
Right this way, everyone.
-首先  容我介绍  -我们是宝石战士
- First, let me introduce ... - We are the Crystal Gems!
石榴
Garnet
紫晶
Amethyst
珍珠
Pearl
还有史蒂文
And Steven!
不过你们已经知道我的名字了
But you already knew my name.
噢  你们都好有才华
Oh! You're all so talented!
所以  你们的确是耍杂技的
So, you are a circus act.
耍杂技的
Circus act?
嘿  我们开吃吧
Hey, let's eat!
-一切都进行得很棒  -谢谢  奇奇
- Everything came out great. - Thanks, Kiki.
姑娘们都不饿吗
Aren't you girls hungry?
你们都没怎么碰吃的
You barely touched your food.
我们不需要吃东西
We don't need to eat.
噢  你们这些年轻人都爱变着花样节食
Oh, you young people and your experimental diets.
我比你老多了
I am much older than you.
这么说  你们都住在山上的小房子里吗
So, you all live in that tiny house up on that hill?
我们所居住的圣所
We inhabit the inner sanctums
只能通过异次元的魔法门进入
only accessible through magical extradimensional doors.
你的手怎么了
What is wrong with your hand?
为什么这地方看着跟快塌了似的
Why's this place look like it's falling apart?
那是因为这神庙已经存在了几千年了
Well, the temple has been here for thousands of years.
噢  原来如此
Oh, I see how it is.
怪不得即使什么东西坏掉
When something breaks around here,
你们也能见怪不怪了
you just leave it alone,
就比如我的小店招牌
just like the sign at my shop!
有谁想打排球吗
Who wants to play volleyball?
好了  各位  球场已经画好了
Okay, everyone, the court is all set.
现在开始组队
Now to get into our teams.
但是  史蒂文
But, Steven,
特殊能力是不是会让我们有不公平的优势啊
won't our abilities give us an unfair advantage?
因此要由我来分组
That's why I'm picking the teams.
紫晶和珍妮一队
Amethyst and Jenny!
珍珠和奇奇一队
Pearl and Kiki!
石榴和科菲一队
Garnet and Kofi!
最后
And last but not least ...
我自己和法奶奶
Yours truly and Nanefua!
我好多年没打了
I haven't played in ages,
但我保证会把你们打得落花流水
but I bet I could whoop all your butts.
这就对啦  大家准备好了吗
That's the spirit. You guys ready?
开打吧
Let's play!
希望你做好输的准备了  珍珠
Hope you're ready to lose, Pearl!
我绝不可能输给你这种人
There's no way I'd lose to someone like you!
开始了
Here we come!
-好球  奇奇  -我扣
- Nice one, Kiki! - And pow!
紫晶  不能踢
Amethyst, no kicking!
这算什么比赛嘛
What kind of game is this?
好球  奇奇
Nicely done, Kiki.
好好遵守规则  紫晶
Try and stick to the rules, Amethyst.
加把劲儿  珍妮
Try harder, Jenny.
来了
Here it comes.
搞什么啊  珍妮
Come on, Jenny!
啥  我什么都没做啊
What? I'm not doing anything.
-哈  看我的  -棒
-  Ha! My move! - Yes!
那样不合适  紫晶
That was uncalled for, Amethyst.
你是怕头发里进沙子吗  奇奇
You afraid of gettin' a little sand in your hair, Kiki?
才不是  只不过想干净些
No, just trying to keep tidy.
保持整洁没有错
There's nothing wrong with trying to keep tidy.
-好激烈啊  -没错
- So exciting! - Yeah!
-轮到我们了  -我准备好了
- Our turn. - I'm ready.
这个我来接
I got this one.
珍妮  你敢碰那球就等着被禁足吧
Jennifer, you touch that ball, you're grounded!
老爸  你耍赖
Whoa! Daddy, you cheatin'!
看你那样儿
The look on your face!
这下容易了
This is going to be easy.
如果他们打得安分些就好了
It'd be nice if they stuck to the basics.
接招吧  石榴
Take this, Garnet.
我们还是躲开吧
We should probably move, huh?
是啊  快跑吧
Yeah, we should.
噢  天哪
Oh! Oh, geez!
看你们逃跑的样子  胆小鬼
You're all running like wild chickens!
你知不知道
Did you know that
沙子在高温下会变成玻璃
when sand is superheated, it turns into glass?
我不知道耶
I did not know that.
开打吧
Let's play!
紫晶
Amethyst!
这里  紫晶  这里
Over here, Amethyst. Over here!
-看我科菲的  -看我珍妮的
- Kofi time! - Jenny time!
-你一个月不准开车  -老爸
- You can't use the car for a month! - Daddy!
你怎么老耍赖啊
Why are you cheating so much?
是你先耍赖的
You cheated first.
才不是呢
That is not true.
局势有些失控了
This is getting out of hand.
我跑过去捡球好了
I'll run and get the ball.
嘿  为什么突然起风了
Hey, why's it getting so... windy?!
不  它回来了
Ah, no! It's back!
-胖河豚怪回来了  -这是怎么
- Puffer fish monster's back! - What's all the ...
法奶奶  快跑
Nanefua, run!
我们最棒  应该是我们赢
We should win 'cause we're the best.
你们都耍赖
Y'all cheated!
-你太过分了 -赖皮鬼
- You're out of line. - Cheaters!
-所有人都被禁足了 -石榴
- Everyone is grounded here. - Garnet!
史蒂文
Steven!
噢  不  宝石战士  保护披萨一家
Oh, no! Gems, protect the Pizzas!
嘿  发生什么了
Hey! What is going on?!
太糟糕了
This is terrible.
我只是想让大家和谐相处
I was trying to get everyone together,
结果却让所有人身处险境
but now everyone's in danger.
我不害怕那玩意儿
I'm not afraid of that thing.
看你能不能赶上我
Let's see if you can keep up with me!
我当然能啦
Of course I can!
过来  这里
Come on, Over here!
不  这里  快点
No! Over here! Come on!
我的天哪  史蒂文
My gosh! Steven!
-他们在做什么  -各位  准备好
- What are they doing? - Everybody, get ready!
妈  你疯了啊
Mom, you are crazy!
不是疯了  是勇敢
Not crazy. Brave.
耿佳  小心背后
Gunga, careful with your back!
-紫晶  把你自己变成一个球  -好的
- Amethyst, turn yourself into a ball! - Okay!
珍妮  把紫晶滚到球网那儿待命
Jenny, roll Amethyst to the net and then hold on!
没问题
Sure thing!
珍珠  跑到珍妮和紫晶那里
Pearl, head over to Jenny and Amethyst!
遵命  女士
Yes, ma'am!
竭尽全力把紫晶打到空中
Hit Amethyst into the air as hard as you can!
乐意效劳
With pleasure.
科菲  奇奇  去球网那里
Kofi, Kiki, get over to the net.
石榴  给沙滩来点儿刺吧
Garnet, spike the beach!
我明白
I understand.
轻一点
Be gentle.
我尽量
I'll try.
-最难的部分来了  -我准备好了
- Here comes the tricky part. - I'm ready!
各位  把球网搬到球场另一边
Everyone, take the net to the other side of the court.
好了  各位  把球网拉向它的脸
Okay, everyone, pull the net into its face!
-还不够  -别担心  还有石榴呢
- It's not enough! - Don't worry! Here comes Garnet!
-多谢你们的款待  -以及
- Thanks for your hospitality. - And?
以及拯救了我一家人
And for saving my family.
你们正式被允许进入我的小店
You are all officially unbanned from my shop.
啊  非常感谢  科菲
Aww! Thank you so much, Kofi!
我们很感谢  对不对  各位
We really appreciate it, right, guys?
-好吧  是的  谢谢  -还有
- Okay. Yes. Thanks. - Aaaand?
我们被禁止去哪儿来着
What were we banned from again?